Guide to the John Penley Photographs and Papers TAM.501
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Photographs, circa 1980-2013; 466650
  - KKK national gathering Pulaski Tennessee, circa 1990-2000; 466767 (Box 11, Folder 316-P)
  - KKK national gathering Pulaski Tennessee, circa 1990-2000; 466766 (Box 17, Folder 317-N)
  - KKK national gathering Pulaski Tennessee, circa 1990-2000; 466765 (Box 11, Folder 317-P)
  - KKK national gathering Pulaski Tennessee KKK yard sale of badges t shirts etc, circa 1990-2000; 466764 (Box 17, Folder 318-N)
  - KKK national gathering Pulaski Tennessee KKK yard sale of badges t shirts etc, circa 1990-2000; 466763 (Box 11, Folder 318-P)
  - Palenque ruins Chiapas Mexico, circa 1990-2000; 466762 (Box 11, Folder 319-P)
  - Protest about Sinead Oconner and pope, alternative fashion show NYC, circa 1990-2000; 466761 (Box 11, Folder 320-P)
  - ACT UP political funeral with real body NYC good photos, circa 1990-2000; 466760 (Box 11, Folder 321-P)
  - Antonio Pagan LES councilman with Guardian Angels Curtis Sliwa and with Lisa (now TV reporter Lisa Evers) at Award ceremony Gramercy Park Hotel, circa 1990-2000; 466759 (Box 11, Folder 322-P)
  - Webster Hall night club with Stephan Prophet working as bathroom attendant other nightlife shots, circa 1990-2000; 466758 (Box 11, Folder 324-P)
  - Viola Plummer's group black nationalists at UN march arrests, circa 1990-2000; 466757 (Box 11, Folder 325-P)
  - Sinead O'Conner support protest at St Patricks, circa 1990-2000; 466756 (Box 11, Folder 326-P)
  - Aron Kay DNC Chicago, circa 1990-2000; 466755 (Box 11, Folder 327-P)
  - Playa Azul Mexico me with girlfriend Marisa Peluso, circa 1990-2000; 466754 (Box 11, Folder 328-P)
  - Ruins at Palenque Chiapas Mexico pyramids, circa 1990-2000; 466753 (Box 11, Folder 329-P)
  - ACT UP political funeral with real body NYC good photos, circa 1990-2000; 466752 (Box 11, Folder 330-P)
  - Squatter protest against Rudy Guiliani also gardens protest Gracie Mansion great historical squatter pix, circa 1990-2000; 466751 (Box 11, Folder 331-P)
  - Puerto Rican funeral Most Holy Redeemer church E 3rd st, circa 1990-2000; 466750 (Box 11, Folder 332-P)
  - Timothy Leary acid guru at Collective Unconscious performance space many shots, circa 1990-2000; 466749 (Box 11, Folder 333-P)
  - Bigotry is not discourse wild art show with naked people, circa 1990-2000; 466748 (Box 11, Folder 334-P)
  - Jesse Jackson DNC Chicago also Sex Pistol band member hired by MTV can't remember his name, circa 1990-2000; 466747 (Box 11, Folder 335-P)
  - Film Director Jim Jarmish with Matt Dillon in nightclub classic pix, circa 1990-2000; 466746 (Box 11, Folder 336-P)
  - Ben and Jerry's concert Central Park, circa 1990-2000; 466745 (Box 11, Folder 337-P)
  - Dean Johnson at Webster Hall wild pix, circa 1990-2000; 466744 (Box 11, Folder 338-P)
  - Ruins at Palenque Chiapas Mexico pyramids, circa 1990-2000; 466743 (Box 11, Folder 339-P)
  - Gay is not the way Yankee fan Freddy at St Patricks day and gay protesters also, Jayson Williams ? Reads from book, wild futuristic sexy fashion show pix, circa 1990-2000; 466742 (Box 11, Folder 340-P)
  - Jim Jarmish and Matt Dillon 9 (classic photos please scan them for online) LES crime scene with detectives, FDNY NY in action on LES multiple photos of Michael Musto Village Voice gossip columnist, circa 1990-2000; 466741 (Box 18, Folder 341-N)
  - Jim Jarmish and Matt Dillon 9 (classic photos please scan them for online) LES crime scene with detectives, FDNY NY in action on LES multiple photos of Michael Musto Village Voice gossip columnist, circa 1990-2000; 466740 (Box 12, Folder 341-P)
  - Democratic National Convention Chicago, Rob McDonald, Bonnie Tocwish, circa 1990-2000; 466739 (Box 18, Folder 342-N)
  - Democratic National Convention Chicago, Rob McDonald, Bonnie Tocwish, circa 1990-2000; 466738 (Box 12, Folder 342-P)
  - Webster Hall wild nightlife, Queer Nation lesbian and gay anti war signs, Lesbian Avengers, circa 1990-2000; 466737 (Box 18, Folder 343-N)
  - Webster Hall wild nightlife, Queer Nation lesbian and gay anti war signs, Lesbian Avengers, circa 1990-2000; 466736 (Box 12, Folder 343-P)
  - Webster Hall, Stephan Prophet of the band False Prophets, circa 1990-2000; 466735 (Box 18, Folder 344-N)
  - Webster Hall, Stephan Prophet of the band False Prophets, circa 1990-2000; 466734 (Box 12, Folder 344-P)
  - Yippie Pieman Aron Kay at Democratic National Convention Chicago, Texas Homegrown Dope George Bush, beautiful Indian traditional dancer shot, circa 1990-2000; 466733 (Box 18, Folder 345-N)
  - Yippie Pieman Aron Kay at Democratic National Convention Chicago, Texas Homegrown Dope George Bush, beautiful Indian traditional dancer shot, circa 1990-2000; 466732 (Box 12, Folder 345-P)
  - Jay Blocher ACT UP public relations press man in Outrage shirt Tompkins Square Park, various shots of TSP tent city and squatters, circa 1990-2000; 466731 (Box 18, Folder 346-N)
  - Jay Blocher ACT UP public relations press man in Outrage shirt Tompkins Square Park, various shots of TSP tent city and squatters, circa 1990-2000; 466730 (Box 12, Folder 346-P)
  - Michael Cezar aka Pope of Pot with Dennis Peron Washington Square Park, Tompkins Square Park 7th Squatter mayday, Chris and Barbara Henry Tompkins Square Tent city both died of AIDS, undated; 466729 (Box 18, Folder 347-N)
  - Michael Cezar aka Pope of Pot with Dennis Peron Washington Square Park, Tompkins Square Park 7th Squatter mayday, Chris and Barbara Henry Tompkins Square Tent city both died of AIDS, undated; 466728 (Box 12, Folder 347-P)
  - Steve Bloom (High Times magazine) David Peel, Joanie Freedom (rainbow family founder] Tompkins Square Park, Chief Esposito NYPD, circa 1990-2000; 466727 (Box 18, Folder 348-N)
  - Steve Bloom (High Times magazine) David Peel, Joanie Freedom (rainbow family founder] Tompkins Square Park, Chief Esposito NYPD, circa 1990-2000; 466726 (Box 12, Folder 348-P)
  - Very rare historical photos of Bob Fass WBAI and Judith Malina of the Living Theater (please please scan on put online) at the Living Theater also Gay Pride Stonewall riot vet, circa 1990-2000; 466725 (Box 18, Folder 349-N)
  - Very rare historical photos of Bob Fass WBAI and Judith Malina of the Living Theater (please please scan on put online] at the Living Theater also Gay Pride Stonewall riot vet, circa 1990-2000; 466724 (Box 12, Folder 349-P)
  - DNC Chicago sign about gays in the military, play about the homeless with homeless actors titled Joe Homeless, circa 1990-2000; 466723 (Box 18, Folder 350-N)
  - DNC Chicago sign about gays in the military, play about the homeless with homeless actors titled Joe Homeless, circa 1990-2000; 466722 (Box 12, Folder 350-P)
  - Bigotry is not discourse art show with naked man, circa 1990-2000; 466721 (Box 18, Folder 351-N)
  - Bigotry is not discourse art show with naked man, circa 1990-2000; 466720 (Box 12, Folder 351-P)
  - Topless lesbian protester at St Patricks parade, Cardinal John O'Conner at St Pats Parade in front of St Pats Cathedral, Irish and heterosexual t shirts lot of good stuff please scan O'Conner and lesbian protester for online, circa 1990-2000; 466719 (Box 18, Folder 353-N)
  - Topless lesbian protester at St Patricks parade, Cardinal John O'Conner at St Pats Parade in front of St Pats Cathedral, Irish and heterosexual t shirts lot of good stuff please scan O'Conner and lesbian protester for online, circa 1990-2000; 466718 (Box 12, Folder 353-P)
  - Webster hall nightlife, Act UP police brutality protest, circa 1990-2000; 466717 (Box 18, Folder 354-N)
  - Webster hall nightlife, Act UP police brutality protest, circa 1990-2000; 466716 (Box 12, Folder 354-P)
  - Abe Libowald Second Ave deli murder crime scene with detectives, circa 1990-2000; 466715 (Box 18, Folder 355-N)
  - Abe Libowald Second Ave deli murder crime scene with detectives, circa 1990-2000; 466714 (Box 12, Folder 355-P)
  - Central American revolutionaries protest dc, Wigstock, Mumia Abu Jamal protest, Palenque Mexico ruins, Fisherman on beach Mexico, circa 1990-2000; 466713 (Box 18, Folder 356-N)
  - Central American revolutionaries protest dc, Wigstock, Mumia Abu Jamal protest, Palenque Mexico ruins, Fisherman on beach Mexico, circa 1990-2000; 466712 (Box 12, Folder 356-P)
  - Latin Kings PR gang meeting at Charas Community Center, Jonathan Shaw famous tattoo artist at his St marks shop tattoo cappachino, circa 1990-2000; 466711 (Box 12, Folder 360-P)
  - Squatter pirate radio station demo against the FCC at Wall Street, circa 1990-2000; 466710 (Box 19, Folder 428-N)
  - Father Pat Maloney, Tompkins Square park homeless disturbance, housing is a human right banner, Joe Papp, Judith Malina, Father George Kuhn, Father Pat Malony, take food to squatters in abandoned school ,gentrification is class war banner, circa 1990-2000; 466709 (Box 19, Folder 429-N)
  - Joe Papp, Judith Malina, Father Pat Maloney, Father George Kuhn take food to homeless barricaded in abandoned school E 4th St contact sheet, circa 1990-2000; 466708 (Box 23, Folder 429-P)
  - [Protest Against First Gulf War] Down with the new world order banner, Class War at home banner, [Allen Ginsberg marches -- his last anti-war march - the night Bush bombed Bagdad 1993], photos from Washington DC and Tompkins Square Park., 1993, circa 1990-2000; 466707 (Box 19, Folder 430-N)
  - [Protest Against First Gulf War] Down with the new world order banner, Class War at home banner, [Allen Ginsberg marches -- his last anti-war march - the night Bush bombed Bagdad 1993], photos from Washington DC and Tompkins Square Park; William Kunstler with Allen Ginsberg and Joey Johnson, Kunstler won a case that made U.S. flag burning legal Johnson was arrested for burning the flag in Texas went to Supreme Court. William Kunstler with Allen Ginsberg and Joey Johnson, Kunstler won a case that made us flag burning legal Johnson was arrested for burning the flag in Texas went to Supreme Court, 1993, circa 1990-2000; 469131 (Box 23, Folder 430-P)
  - Chinese staff and workers at Community Board Three, circa 1990-2000; 466705 (Box 19, Folder 431-N)
  - KKK cross burning Palaski Tennessee, circa 1990-2000; 466704 (Box 19, Folder 432-N)
  - No Condo 2 [nd Avenue?] & [Avenue?] B Tom[kins Square Park Rally, July 1997; 469132 (Box 19, Folder 432.1-N)
  - Squatter Pig Roast Tompkins Square Park, circa 1990-2000; 466703 (Box 19, Folder 433-N)
  - Mothers of kids killed by cops march against police brutality, circa 1990-2000; 466702 (Box 19, Folder 434-N)
  - Tenth annual squatter mayday and squatter pig roast, circa 1990-2000; 466701 (Box 23, Folder 434-P)
  - Fifth Ave and Washington Square Park pot parade, circa 1990-2000; 466700 (Box 19, Folder 435-N)
  - Anti gulf war rally DC Queers for peace, circa 1990-2000; 466699 (Box 19, Folder 438-N)
  - Chinese staff and workers protest at Community Board Three, anti police brutality rally Lower East Side, circa 1990-2000; 466698 (Box 23, Folder 438-P)
  - Woman nodding in doorway LES, circa 1990-2000; 466697 (Box 23, Folder 439-P)
  - Washington Square rally, bottles lined up on ave a to throw at cops later an all night riot, circa 1990-2000; 466696 (Box 19, Folder 441-N)
  - Carmen Pabon, Willie Butler, Michael Shenker at squatter rally, circa 1990-2000; 466695 (Box 19, Folder 441-N)
  - Gay hippie love in and anti violence against Asians rally, circa 1990-2000; 466694 (Box 19, Folder 443-N)
  - After eviction squatters camp out in front of building with the war on the poor comes home banner, music band shots for album cover Dem Vakra band, circa 1990-2000; 466693 (Box 19, Folder 444-N)
  - Museum of Urban Reclaimed Space postcards with my picture of tank vs squatters on it, circa 1990-2000; 466692 (Box 23, Folder 444-P)
  - Housing rally, circa 1990-2000; 466691 (Box 19, Folder 445-N)
  - Stop sexist cops rally, circa 1990-2000; 466690 (Box 19, Folder 446-N)
  - After the first World Trade Center bombing, circa 1990-2000; 466689 (Box 19, Folder 448-N)
  - Dean Johnson Dean and the Weenies band shots, circa 1990-2000; 466688 (Box 19, Folder 449-N)
  - ACT UP aids protest with many signs and arrests, circa 1990-2000; 466687 (Box 19, Folder 450-N)
  - First gay pride march Asheville NC many hate signs exp. AIDS kills fags dead, circa 1990-2000; 466686 (Box 19, Folder 451-N)
  - 9th pct arrest, circa 1990-2000; 466685 (Box 19, Folder 453-N)
  - ACT UP rally AIDS cuts=death Rudy this is war banner and street art, circa 1990-2000; 466684 (Box 19, Folder 455-N)
  - 1988=1933 new school forum with Clayton Patterson, Washington Square Park anti curfew protest with squatter Jerry the Peddler in tree, 6th pct police, 466683 (Box 19, Folder 456-N)
  - 7th street squat fire, guardian angels, revolutionary homeless organizing committee with banner, subway shots of clown, circa 1990-2000; 466682 (Box 19, Folder 457-N)
  - Gay Pride drag queen march very colorful costumes, circa 1990-2000; 466681 (Box 19, Folder 458-N)
  - HPD Housing Prevention Demolition march with HPD banner, Squatters burn american flag other stuff Tompkins Square Park, circa 1990-2000; 466680 (Box 19, Folder 459-N)
  - Frame 12a strip Bob Fass WBAI, Squatter concert Moogie Klingman's band Moogie on keyboard, Russian Art party Pravda homosexual ideology art show with beautiful body painted topless musicians, circa 1990-2000; 466679 (Box 19, Folder 460-N)
  - Council member Tom Duane boycott Colorado rally, author of The Great Peace March at bookstore reading author ?, circa 1990-2000; 466678 (Box 19, Folder 461-N)
  - NARL pro and anti abortion protesters, We want our park back Tompkins square rally, lots of signs, circa 1990-2000; 466677 (Box 19, Folder 463-N)
  - Power to the people banner Lori Rizzo, No police state banner, skinheads not sure if they are racist or anti racist skins, circa 1990-2000; 466676 (Box 19, Folder 464-N)
  - Police Cover Up Who Killed Grady Alexis rally, circa 1990-2000; 466675 (Box 19, Folder 465-N)
  - Mohawk Indian Protest about standoff at OKA Canada taken in Montreal, circa 1990-2000; 466674 (Box 19, Folder 466-N)
  - Anti Columbus day indian protest Stanley Cohen, the new world order ends here banner, circa 1990-2000; 466673 (Box 19, Folder 467-N)
  - Condos out of the Lower East Side march, Borough president Betsy Gotbaum in Tompkins Square park, Uncle Don Yippie (24a) in front of line of cops, Squatter Willie Butler dying of AIDS in hospital, 1990; 466672 (Box 19, Folder 468-N)
  - First Gay pride march Asheville NC lots of hate signs, Art Auction for Tompkins Square Tent City homeless Max Fish bar, circa 1990-2000; 466671 (Box 19, Folder 470-N)
  - Unable to Identify, circa 1990-2000; 466670 (Box 19, Folder 471-N)
  - Community music and dance event Charas Community Center, circa 1990-2000; 466669 (Box 19, Folder 472-N)
  - Abner Louima famous victim of police brutality, circa 1990-2000; 466668 (Box 19, Folder 473-N)
  - Jorge Brandon aka El Coco que Habla the father of nyourican poets movement on park bench with sign TSP, cop car with grafitti nazi symbol, lots of high ranking NYPD, circa 1990-2000; 466667 (Box 20, Folder 474-N)
  - John the Communist with resist police terror banner, murals TSP, Orthodox jews at beth Israel hospital wait for the resurrection of their rebbe he died but did not walk out of the hospital resurrected like he told them would happen, circa 1990-2000; 466666 (Box 20, Folder 474-N)
  - Party at Clayton Patterson's gallery many old skool artists and beatnicks, circa 1990-2000; 466665 (Box 20, Folder 475-N)
  - Staten Island ferry boats, Statue of Liberty black and white, circa 1990-2000; 466664 (Box 20, Folder 477-N)
  - B and w Ed Koch A9 frame, Rudy Guliani A10 frame, lots of NYC politicians, Jobs are a right union rally, circa 1990-2000; 466663 (Box 20, Folder 478-N)
  - Veterans day parade b and w lots of Bush patriotic images, anti imperialism march very historical b and w images, circa 1990-2000; 466662 (Box 20, Folder 482-N)
  - Building in Toronto, circa 1990-2000; 466661 (Box 20, Folder 536-N)
  - Smokestack wasteland Toronto, circa 1990-2000; 466660 (Box 20, Folder 537-N)
  - Brazilian parade East Village, circa 1990-2000; 466659 (Box 20, Folder 538-N)
  - Nicaragua, 1983; 466658 (Box 23, Folder 540-P)
  - Allen Ginsberg reading at Clive Barker book party, Curtis and Lisa Sliwa guardian angels, circa 1990-2000; 466657 (Box 23, Folder 541-P)
  - Jonny Rotten of the sex pistols DNC Chicago, circa 1990-2000; 466656 (Box 23, Folder 542-P)
  - Sister Mary Kelleher at CB3 meeting, murder suspect 9th pct, 9th pct commander Sita with housing lawyer Jacque Buchoski, circa 1990-2000; 466655 (Box 23, Folder 543-P)
  - Mosaic man Jim Powers signs petition to allow bar to open on Ave A, circa 1990-2000; 466654 (Box 23, Folder 544-P)
  - Sex panic forum, circa 1990-2000; 466653 (Box 23, Folder 545-P)
  - Dean Johnson, William Kunstler, Free Mumia rally Philly, Building collapse Houston St., circa 1990-2000; 466652 (Box 23, Folder 546-P)
  - Allen Ginsberg reading in TSP [misc. from Box 1], circa 1990-2000; 466651 (Box 8, Folder 662-P)
  - Undescribed, circa 1980-2010; 468943 (Box 9, Folder 178-P to 255-P)
  - Undescribed, circa 1980-2010; 468944 (Box 16, Folder 191-N to 273-N)
  - Undescribed, circa 1980-2010; 468945 (Box 21, Folder 551-N to 604-N)
  - Undescribed, circa 1980-2010; 468946 (Box 22, Folder 605-N to 661-N)
  - Undescribed (Oversize), circa 1980-2010; 468947 (Box OS004, Folder 663-P and 664-P)
  - Pictures on CD, Mini-DV Cassette Tapes, Rolled Negatives, 664-N (unidentified), and Negative from 049-S, 2013, undated; 467103 (Box 23)
  - John Penley 2013 Donation, 2009-2013; 485631; 3 boxes
    Materials in this subseries consist of three boxes containing 35 mm negatives and prints (mostly color) shot by John Penley between 2009 and 2013, CDs with images scanned from the negatives, and a section of a newspaper and two postcards. Photos labeled 2009-2010 relate primarily to life in Manhattan's Lower East Side while others dated 2011-2013 cover protests in support of Chelsea Manning and Occupy Wall Street. Also included in these materials are two CDs of images taken with a digital camera. One of these CDs covers the first day of the Chelsea Manning trial protest on June 1, 2013, and the other labeled "Ashville Drums" is undated.
    - Scanned Photographs, 2009-2011; 2013.019; 482261; 1 box (Box 24)
    - Scanned Photographs, 2011-2013; 2013.019; 482718; 1 box (Box 25)
    - Negatives, Prints, and Clippings, 2009-2012; 2013.019; 482719; 1 box (Box 26)
- Series III: Archived Website, Mar 15, 2013-ongoing; 547007
  John Penley is a photographer and grassroots political activist associated with the squatters' rights movement and housing protests of the 1980s and 1990s in New York City's East Village and Lower East Side, as well as numerous other social causes. A former Navy serviceman, Penley took up photography as part of an effort to document the demonstrations, protests, and other political actions in which he took part, and in the process became a photojournalist. Hundreds of Penley's photographs have appeared in in publications including the New York Daily News, the New York Post, the New York Times, New York and Long Island Newsday, New York Magazine, The Villager, High Times Magazine, The Guardian, Art In America, WW 3 Illustrated, The Shadow, the East Village Eye, and many small political publications. They have also been distributed through press services such as United Press International and the Associated Press. The website contains photographs taken by Penley.